referpartners.com 2013-11-26

# Privacy Policy

**How we collect and use information**

All the personal data we collect about will be collected from you fairly and lawfully and not in any unjustly invasive method. You recognize and concur that we might gather this data from you in with relation to or as a result of your usage of our site, including, without limitation, the supply of the online services to you. We are the exclusive proprietor of the data gathered on this site. We will not share, share or lease this data to others in any, other than the sharing of affiliate names with their respective introducer. Information is gathered at various junctures within our site, from our users. We gather data about you upon registration and we also collect information from all forms of communication, such as e-mails and via telephone, from you or from a 3rd party about you. We may also gather data from you if you participate in surveys and special promotions undertaken on our site. We may also gather financial information about you if you decide to obtain payments via wire transfer. Further data that we may collect is detailed below. 

**Registration**

The registration form must be completed in order to use our site. Upon registration we gather personal data such as your contact details including your name, your address and email telephone and fax numbers. We use this information to correspond with you about the services on our, any changes made, and for general correspondence. All mandatory information is declared within the registration form and is essential in order to complete the registration procedure. We do encourage you to supply the extra, non-compulsory information listed on the registration form to help us provide you with a more specialized and personalized service. 

**Cookies**

A **cookie** , also known as an **HTTP cookie** , **web cookie** , or **browser cookie** , is used for a website to send data to a user's browser and for the browser to return the data to the origin site. Cookies are used to store certain information such as your Affiliate Number so that you do not need to re-type this every time you log in. If cookies are disabled, you may still browse our site, but you will be unable to log in. In order to log in to our site, cookies need to be enabled. 

**Log Files**

Statistical data is collected by us about you. All page, image or cgi program requests to our servers by your browser are logged in a log file, which also gathers the following information: 

Your remote IP address,   
The referring HTML page   
The type of browser and computer that you are using.   
IP addresses are used to administer our site, analyze trends, and collect general demographic information for general usage. The statistical data we collect is for internal marketing analysis and this information and IP addresses are not linked to information which is personally identifiable. 

**Sharing**

We may share summative demographic data with our business partners and clients. If we do, your personal details will only be used as part of a summative collection of data and you will not be personally identifiable. We may share details about you when obligated by law to do so. Otherwise, we may share data about you, at our discretion, should we consider that such sharing of data is reasonably suitable or necessary to:   
(a) Apply or Enforce the Terms and Conditions of Use of the Site;   
or   
(b) To protect the rights, property or safety of Referpartners.com, our users, our merchants, or others. 

**External Links**

This web site may contain links to other websites. Please be aware that we are in no way, responsible for the privacy policies and practices or the content of other websites. We recommend that when you exit our site for you to read and be aware of the the privacy policies of all websites that gather data that is personally identifiable. This privacy policy is applicable solely to data gathered by this site only. 

**Service and Site Notifications**

From time to time we may also send you service and site notifications. You cannot unsubscribe from these announcements due to the important information contained about services and our site. 

**Surveys & Competitions**

Occasionally we may request information from you via surveys or competitions. It is not compulsory to participate in these surveys or competitions. Information requested may include contact details and demographic data. Information gathered from surveys may be used for the purposes of checking or improving the site, its use and the satisfaction when using. 

**Safety &Security**

We take safety and security of our website very seriously and do all we can to ensure a safe and protected environment. We endeavor to ensure we take every precaution to prevent the misuse, loss, and modification of all data under our management. When sensitive information is submitted to or via our site, the information is secured both offline and online. We use encryption to guard sensitive online data and also do all we can to safeguard offline information regarding users. We also ensure that the servers are held in a safe and secure environment. Should you have any questions or comments regarding the security at our site, please send an email to: [support@referpartners.com](mailto:support@referpartners.com). 

**Supplementation of Information**

Occasionally, it is necessary for us to supplement the information we receive with information from third party sources In order for this site to properly fulfill its obligation to our customers. All new members receive a welcome email which is used to verify username and password. Existing members may, from time to time, receive information on our clients and their services. All users can choose not to receive these types of correspondence, information of which can be found the following updating personal information.

**Updating Personal Information  
**   
If you wish to update your personal information or you no longer wish to use our services, you may update or remove your personal information given to us. This can be achieved by emailing our Customer Support at [support@referpartners.com](mailto:support@referpartners.com). 

**Notification of Changes**

We reserve the right to modify our privacy policy at any time, without any notice. Should such changes take place, we will post those changes here in our privacy policy in order to ensure you are always aware of what data is collected, how it is used, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose such information.
